Hubert Nguyen

11119 Alterra Parkway Austin Tx. 78758 hubertanguyen@gmail.com Ph: 713-444-3917

Front-End Developer

I am a front-end developer with extensive experience building responsive websites and JavaScript applications. I understand the importance of cross browser compatibility, and strive to follow best practices in developing for the web. For me, this means taking into consideration accessibility as well as overall functionality for the end user.

Languages/FrameWorks

- JavaScript (including ES6)
- HTML5, CSS3
- Sass
- Angular.js
- Node.js
- Grunt, Gulp

Work Experience

Volusion, Austin, Texas

Jun 2015 - Present

Front-End Developer

As a front-end developer at Volusion I work with designers to code out custom storefront templates, and also develop internal applications and web components for the e-commerce platform.

I work on a team that implements Scrum methodologies. I helped the team coordinate the workflow to include: automation with Grunt, BEM via Sass, and version control with Git. Furthermore, I am responsible for providing architecture and direction to the JavaScript code base. This includes using modules, utilizing NPM, and creating documentation.

Some of the technologies I use include: Angular.js, Node.js, PhantomJS, Jasmine, Grunt, Gulp, Yeoman, Bootstrap, Sass, Bourbon, Git.

Moblize, Houston, Texas

Aug 2014 - Nov 2014

Front-End Developer

Moblize is a company that provides data integrity for oil and gas companies through software as a service. Their web applications are used by drilling engineers to ensure optimum efficiency on oil rigs.

At Moblize, I implemented data visualization using JavaScript and the High-Charts API. In addition, I used Java along with the Play! web framework. I was also involved in weekly Scrum meetings where we assigned client user stories among the team members, managed requirements, and estimated hours for completion.

Poetic Systems, Houston, Texas

Jul 2014 - Aug 2014

Intern Web Developer

As an intern I was responsible for the testing of Ruby on Rails applications using test-driven development. I used RSpec and FactoryGirl to develop a test suite for an existing Rails application.

Physican Clinic: Dzung Nguyen MD, Houston, Texas

Jun 2009 - Feb 2011

Laboratory Assistant

As a laboratory assistant for a large physician clinic, I was responsible for the accession, labeling, and processing of several physicians' supply requests. In addition, I supported other lab personnel. This included maintaining specimen integrity by using proper technique, and following department procedures.

UCSD, San Diego, California

Mar 2007 - May 2009

Laboratory Assistant

I served as a research assistant at the Poligano lab at UCSD. The Poligano lab is focused on spore research for E.coli. My responsibilities included running western blots and PCR assays for spores.

Independent Developer

Hundred Million Mile Club

2014 - '15

Hundred Million Mile Club was a "Coding for a Cause" project for the San Francisco public school system. Coding for a Cause is a program where small teams volunteer their time to help non-profits bring their ideas to life through custom made web applications.

The Hundred Million Mile Club was a web platform designed to help schools across the nation motivate their students to exercise and live a healthier lifestyle. Schools could input a goal for the number of miles students aimed to collectively run each day. As a school reported miles ran, they received various animated trophies and badges.

Technologies: D3.js, JavaScript, jQuery, Sass, Ruby, PostGres, HTML5, CSS3

Win-Food 2014 - '15

Win-Food is a web application that helps users find the best rated restaurants by combining the Yelp and Google Map APIs. Yelp data is visualized though Google maps. Ratings are represented by dynamic icons; smaller icons represent lower ratings and larger icons match with higher ratings.

Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby / Sinatra Framework, HTML5, CSS3

Education

Hack Reactor (formerly MakerSquare), Austin, Texas

Feb 2014 - Feb 2014

Hack Reactor is a highly selective school that trains web developers through an in-person, full time bootcamp. Graduates of Hack Reactor learn how to build every part of a web application using modern web technologies and source control practices.

University of California at San Diego, San Diego, California

Sep 2006 - Sep 2009

B.S., Biology

Grossmont Community College, San Diego, California

Aug 2002 - Jun 2005

San Diego, California, Life Sciences